welcome to the listening Time Podcast
hey everybody this is Connor and you're
listening to
episode23 of the listening Time Podcast
I hope you're all doing great uh at the
time of recording this it's the very end
of summer here in the northern
hemisphere uh and so autumn is just
around the corner in English when we say
that something is just around the corner
we're saying that it's about to appear
or it's about to happen it's going to
happen very soon so fall is just around
the corner and a lot of people are
really happy about this because a lot of
people here like this season they like
Autumn they like to see the color colors
changing they like the seasonal food uh
there are a lot of uh different types of
food um that people start to eat during
Autumn that they don't eat during the
spring or summer and so uh a lot of
people like this season one fun thing
about this season is that there are a
lot of activities for children for
example pumpkin patches the these uh
places where they sell pumpkins but they
also have a lot of activities uh for
kids and me and my family we're planning
on going to a couple pumpkin patches
this season and I think that I'll do an
episode on pumpkin patches so you'll get
to hear about that hopefully and I was
thinking about this topic of fun AC
activities for children uh because I was
thinking about pumpkin patches uh and
about different things like that and I
decided that I wanted to do an episode
uh about some of my favorite uh
activities that I did when I was a kid
so my childhood activities specifically
things that I did Outdoors things that I
did outside
I thought it would be fun to uh look
back and remember uh my childhood and
some of my favorite things that I did
outside uh so I hope that this will be
an interesting episode for you today and
before we start I want to remind you
that my new podcast is available now us
conversations where I talk to different
English teachers from around the us and
we talk about many things and have
natural conversations at normal speed
and you have the transcript available
with the definitions of keyword and
phrases that we use so make sure to sign
up for that if you're interested the
link is in the episode description below
this episode that's
patreon.com us
conversations and if you want my
specialized training to help you
understand native speakers when they
speak fast then make sure to join my
membership the link is also in the
description below this episode so click
on that and join if you're interested in
getting my specialized training and of
course if you're a Spanish or a
Portuguese speaker you can also check
out my ebook if you want to start
reading fiction in English those links
are down below as well and if you like
this podcast please share it with anyone
else you know who's learning English and
please give it a five-star rating and
write a review all right let's get
started are your ears ready you know
what time it is it's listening
time all right let's talk about some of
my favorite childhood activities that I
did some of my favorite things that I
did Outdoors because I did some things
indoors as well I had some uh fun
activities that I did inside but I want
to focus on the outdoor activities today
so the first one that I want to talk
about is building a
treehouse so you've probably seen this
in movies or TV shows before uh where
the kids build uh some type of house in
their backyard maybe uh in a big tree
and this is something that is a pretty
classic tradition here in the US uh
people like tree houses this is a fun
thing for kids however I built a
treehouse that was a little bit
different from what you're probably
imagining we didn't build a house that
was uh a
closed um box like you see in the movies
usually we built a treeh house uh where
we just had these different platforms on
different branches uh of the tree uh a
platform is just a flat uh space and in
this case a space where you can stand on
so my friend and I we uh built this
treehouse that had many different
platforms uh at different levels and on
different branches and we would have to
uh climb to the different platforms
using
these steps that we also built we used
wood and nailed the wood into the tree
to build steps that we could step on by
the way when we say that you nail
something we're saying that you use a
nail this sharp little uh tool and you
use that and you hit it
into the object you nail it so we nailed
these wooden steps into the tree trunk
so that we could climb the tree uh to
get to the different
platforms I know that this might be a
little difficult to visualize but that's
probably the best way that I can
describe it and building this treehouse
was really fun I think think we had more
fun building The Treehouse than we did
playing in the treeh house so it was
really fun to construct this and we were
pretty young when we built this I think
I was like 10 years old maybe so we were
young uh it was probably a little
dangerous but uh we did it anyway and uh
this was the first first time that I
really used a hammer and nails on my own
so I learned how to hammer things when I
built this
treehouse and it was uh a great place to
play and to use our imagination to
create games and things like that in
this treehouse and in general I always
really liked climbing trees as a kid
that was always something that I enjoyed
and so this was a perfect project for me
because I got the chance to climb this
tree and also build something use my
imagination play Etc so that was one of
my favorite activities as a kid another
childhood activity that I wanted to
mention is that I actually collect Ed
bugs for a time uh the word bug just
means insect right so I actually
collected bugs uh during a brief time in
my life um now when I look back on this
it seems kind of gross to me the word
gross just means disgusting so it seems
kind of gross when I think back to all
the bugs that I collected uh I remember
that in particular I collected
caterpillars you know these things that
turn into butterflies right so I
collected
caterpillars and I remember putting them
in a container and I tried to uh create
a good environment for them in this
container I put leaves and sticks and
things like that inside and I fed them
fruit I remember feeding them cantaloupe
actually if you don't know what a
cantaloupe is this is that type of uh
melon that's orange on the inside that's
cantaloupe so I remember feeding them
cantaloupe and cleaning the container
and and I don't know why I was so
interested in them but for some reason I
like to collect them and watch them
interact with each other in this
container and I also remember collecting
some
beetles uh I remember doing that I don't
remember all of the other specific bugs
that I collected but I just remember
that I liked to watch them interact with
each other I would combine some
different bugs together and watch what
they did to see if they would um get
along or if they would fight or whatever
by the way the phrasal verb get along
means that you uh are in harmony with
another person or another animal so it
means that you don't fight with each
other you get along so I think that I
liked to experiment a little bit and see
if these bugs uh would get along with
each other so that's another activity
that I did as a kid and another one was
making paper
airplanes so I loved making paper
airplanes as a kid uh especially because
I love loved uh trying to find the
different combinations of folds that
would result in the best
airplane uh I don't know if you have
much experience making paper
airplanes but of course it really um
matters how you fold uh the paper so if
you fold the paper in certain ways and
you follow certain design you can make a
pretty impressive airplane actually uh
some airplanes that we made actually uh
stayed in the air for quite a while and
I remember that we had one design in
particular that was the best one so my
neighbor and I uh found this uh Perfect
Design that uh we would recreate uh time
and time again and create these
airplanes and try to make them fly as
high and as long as possible and so uh
it was a very intricate design uh the
word intricate means that something is
very
detailed and so this was an intricate
design I still remember how to make this
paper airplane even now as an adult uh
that's how many times I made it uh I
made it so many times that uh I still
have that muscle memory I still remember
exactly how to make this airplane so uh
we found that Perfect Design and we
always tried to uh improve it or find an
even better design so we found found
some other combinations of folds that
worked pretty well but we never ended up
uh beating that one really good design
that we found um but it was really fun
to do that and to experiment with
different uh types of designs I really
like that I like experimenting with
different options and trying to create
different designs uh with things like
that that's something that I enjoy and I
really enjoyed it as a kid so that was
another good activity that I had and
another one was something that we called
cardboard so we would slide down this
big hill on pieces of cardboard
cardboard Bo is that material uh that is
used to package items to uh transport
them or ship them to another place by
the way when we say
shipping uh when we say that in item
ships we're saying that it is sent from
one place to another so cardboard is
that material that's used to ship items
to package them and ship them
so we would uh cut big pieces of
cardboard from these different boxes and
we would sit on them and then slide down
this big hill that was behind my house
so this was something that uh my friend
came up with by the way when we say that
you come up with something were saying
that you think of an idea so this is
something that he came up with and I uh
joined in and we had a lot of fun doing
this it didn't always work really well
because sometimes uh the grass uh grew
in a way that didn't allow us to slide
very well so we had to work around that
and and do our best to um be able to
make it to the bottom of the hill on
this cardboard um but it was actually a
little bit dangerous because we weren't
able to stop very well um you don't
really have a break
system with this type of cardboard
obviously so if we made it to the bottom
of the hill on the
cardboard sometimes we wouldn't be able
to stop well and we would kind of um
fall off of it uh and maybe uh it would
hurt a little bit uh or we might run
into something and we would crash right
so it was a little bit dangerous and I
think there were a few times when uh I
got hurt but nothing nothing serious
just minor things but that was an
activity that was uh a fun one in the
sense that we created it and it wasn't
something that other people really did
uh we didn't learn about it from anyone
else my friend uh just created it he had
this idea and we just did it and we were
the only ones that we knew who did this
type of activity so uh that was pretty
cool it was born out of kids imagination
right it was just something that we
decided to do because it sounded fun and
we had the material and we made it work
we uh did it until um we found the
perfect way to do it and then we had fun
with it
uh I really uh like when kids come up
with uh interesting games and activities
like that uh I think that's really cool
and speaking of that uh the last
activity that I want to talk about uh is
playing make believe in English when we
say that you make believe or you play
make believe we're saying that you
create situations and games from your
imagination uh things that aren't real
but you imagine them and then you play
uh this game or you uh do this activity
so I played make believe a lot when I
was around the age of six uh or seven
around that age I remember uh playing
with my old old neighbor in my old house
uh my first house and I remember uh
inventing different games together where
we would have to make believe we had to
pretend and
imagine uh these different
situations by the way in this context
the word pretend means that you imagine
something that isn't real but you act
like it's real okay so for example if I
pretend that I'm a superhero this means
that I'm acting and imagining that I'm a
superhero even though it's not real
right so I remember
pretending and uh coming up with all of
these different scenarios with my
neighbor and we uh just went through
these whole
story lines and pretended that we were
different characters doing different
things and it was tons of fun I remember
that our favorite thing to uh pretend
was that we were on a big boat we called
it the boat game and we pretended that
we were these Sailors on this big boat
and we were navigating the Open Seas and
we encountered all of these different
complications and problems I don't know
where we got that idea from I have no
idea how we started that but I just
remember that we loved playing this boat
game and using our
imagination so I really like that type
of activity that make believe type of
activity
because I think it's really good for
kids it helps kids use their imagination
and not just rely on uh being given the
stimulation from a screen or from
something else uh kids have to think of
things on their own and create things
from nothing I really like that and I
think it's also beneficial
in the sense that it helps kids become
more social right you have to work with
your friends uh and you have to um agree
with each other and get along with each
other while you're uh imagining these
situations and playing um in this
context and I think it also helps kids
uh become a little more
independent and it helps them uh begin
to play on their own and not just need
their parents to play with them for
example so I think that there are a lot
of good benefits for kids uh to play
make believe I really like that and uh
I'm interested to see when my son will
start to play Make Believe and create
scenarios like that uh that are
imaginary uh I'm looking forward to that
stage in his life I think that will be
fun all right why don't I stop there I
hope this episode was interesting for
you remember that you can sign up for my
new podcast us conversations it's an
exclusive podcast so you need to sign up
and you'll get one new conversation
every month where I talk to a different
person from a different part of the
United States and you have the
transcript available with the
definitions of keywords and phrases that
we use so the link is in the description
below this episode that's
patreon.com USC
conversations and if you want help
understanding native speakers if you
want my training then make sure to sign
up for my membership uh the link is also
down below and if you like this podcast
I'd appreciate it if you could share it
with anyone else you know who's learning
English and please give it a five-star
rating and write a review all right
thank you for listening to this episode
and I'll talk to you on the next episode
of listening
time